<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Machine-Learning on Content</title><link>https://garthjacques.github.io/tags/machine-learning/</link><description>Recent content in Machine-Learning on Content</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://garthjacques.github.io/tags/machine-learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A-MEM: Agentic Memory for LLM Agents</title><link>https://garthjacques.github.io/library/a-mem-agentic-memory-for-llm-agents/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garthjacques.github.io/library/a-mem-agentic-memory-for-llm-agents/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="a-mem-agentic-memory-for-llm-agents"&gt;A-MEM: Agentic Memory for LLM Agents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authors:&lt;/strong&gt; Wujiang Xu, Zuzie Liang, Kai Mei, Hang Gao, Juntao Tan, Yongfeng Zhang&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Affiliations:&lt;/strong&gt; Rutgers University, AntGroup, Salesforce Research&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id="abstract"&gt;Abstract&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While large language model (LLM) agents can effectively use external tools for complex real-world tasks, they require memory systems to leverage historical experiences. Current memory systems enable basic storage and retrieval but lack sophisticated memory organization, despite recent attempts to incorporate graph databases. Moreover, these systems&amp;rsquo; fixed operations and structures limit their adaptability across diverse tasks. To address this limitation, this paper proposes a novel agentic memory system for LLM agents that can dynamically organize memories in an agentic way.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>AI Agents vs. Agentic AI: A Conceptual taxonomy, applications and challenges</title><link>https://garthjacques.github.io/library/ai-agents-vs-agentic-ai-a-conceptual-taxonomy-applications-and-challenges/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garthjacques.github.io/library/ai-agents-vs-agentic-ai-a-conceptual-taxonomy-applications-and-challenges/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="foundational-understanding-of-ai-agents"&gt;Foundational understanding of AI Agents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI Agents can be defined as autonomous software entities engineered for goal-directed task execution within bounded digital environments. These agents are defined by their ability to perceive structured or unstructured inputs, to reason over contextual information, and to initiate actions toward achieving specific objectives, often acting as surrogates for human users or subsystems. Unlike conventional automation scripts, which follow deterministic workflows, AI Agents demonstrate reactive intelligence and some level of adaptability, allowing them to interpret dynamic inputs and reconfigure outputs accordingly. Their adoption has been reported across a wide range of application domains, including customer service automation, personal productivity assistance, organizational information retrieval, and decision support systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>